

# **Gulbala Salamov**

### **Software Developer**

Office Location: Saint Petersburg, Russia Place of Residence: Ankara, Turkey Nationality: Turkish, Azerbaijan

# Personal Profile

I am a Software Developer with a Researcher experience from reputable universities. I have improved skills in problem identification and implementation of effective solutions. I have good interpersonal communication and social skills.

I'd like to invest in myself further with top skills modern engineers need to succeed. I have 3 years experience in agile software engineering practices from conception to completion and 1 year active professional programming experience. Recently my focus shifts into best practices applied in the industry.

### **Education**

BS, Computer Education & Instructional Technologies 2010 – 2014 Middle East Technical University, Turkey

MSc, Computer Science 2014 – 2016 Swansea University, U.K.

# Professional Experience

Software Developer & Technical Writer – eSystems Nordic Feb. 2022 – till present (Full Time, Remote)

Researcher & Jr. Software Developer – University College London, U.K. Apr 2019 - June 2020 (Full Time)

Researcher & Developer Intern – State University of New York, U.S.A June 2017 - Sep 2017 (Full Time)

Jr. Software Development Specialist – SIP Azerbaijan Sep 2013 - Sep 2016 (Part Time, Project based)

ICT Teacher Intern – Middle East Technical University, Turkey Feb 2014 - June 2014 (Part Time)

ICT Teacher Intern – Private Ari Schools, Turkey Feb 2014 - June 2014 (Part Time)

### Contact

- +90 536 710 2202
- <sup>1</sup> github.com/gulbalasalamov
- <sup>2</sup> <u>linkedin.com/in/gulbalasalamov</u>
- <sup>3</sup> g.salamov@gmail.com

# Languages

- TURKISH MOTHER
- AZERBAIJAN MOTHER
- ENGLISH BUSINESS
- RUSSIAN INTERMEDIATE
- GERMAN BEGINNER

### 5 Words to Describe Me

- Problem solver
- Consistent
- Kind
- Positive
- Enthusiastic

### Industry Experience

- ICT Services
- Education
- Healthcare & Life Sciences
- Travel & Hospitality

# **Major Projects**

### ECSAnVIs

Extreme Citizen Science Analysis and Visualisation (ECSAnVis) is a five-years, €2.5M project funded by the European Research Council (ERC), aiming at the development of geographical analysis and visualisation tools that can be used, successfully, by non-literate people and any other community in a culturally appropriate ways, that further fit their needs and social practices.

The work further builds on Sapelli, an open-source Android project that facilitates data collection through highly configurable icon-driven user interfaces. The transmission of complete records is handled autonomously to another phone using sms or a GeoKey web server.

https://www.geog.ucl.ac.uk/research/research-centres/excites/projects/extreme-citizen-science-analysis-and-visualisation-ecsanvis

### My role - Android Developer

Apr 2019 - June 2020

- Designed and implemented interactive prototypes for Sapelli Visualiser to display collected geographically meaningful.
- Maintained Sapelli Collector, fixed bugs, added new functionalities.
- Picked up existing code base, wrote better and maintainable code.
- Improved the documentation further using GitHub as a source management repository.
- Contributed to academic research, presentations and workshops

#### Applications:

o Android, Java, SQL, Python, Adobe XD, Git

# X Skillset (Level 1-5)

1 - Poor, 2 - Modest, 3 - Average, 4 - Good, 5 - Excellent

A. PROGRAMMING LANGUAGES	LEVEL OF COMPETENCE
Android	••••
Java	•••00
SQL	•••00
Version CS (Git, Github)	••••
Code Organization (OOP, FP, Design Patterns)	••••
Testing Framework (Debugging, Junit5)	••000

### What Motivates Me

- Solving real life problems by building software solutions
- Researching and creating contents both educational and scientific
- Learning and sharing my knowledge

# SuperPowers

Interpersonal Communication

**Social Skills** 

Team Player

Fast Learner

B. SERVER SIDE TECHNOLOGIES	LEVEL OF COMPETENCE
Java	•••00
Framework (Spring)	••000
Spring Framework Core (Configuration, MVC, DI)	••000
Spring Boot Databases (Spring Data JPA, PostgreSQL, MySQL)	••••
Spring Security (JWT, Auth & Authentication)	••000

C. FRONT END TECHNOLOGIES	LEVEL OF COMPETENCE
Language (CSS, HTML)	••••
Framework (Angular)	•0000
Prototype (AdobeXD, Figma)	••••

D. LOW-CODE & NO-CODE TECH	LEVEL OF COMPETENCE
OutSystems	••000

E. OTHER SKILLS	LEVEL OF COMPETENCE
OAS & Swagger	•••00
R & D, Academic Writings	••••
Soft Skills (Communication, Patience, Time Management, Open Minded)	••••
Additional Tools (Jira, Slack, Teams)	••••

# What am I most proud of

I've a passion to share my knowledge. So, to help novice programmers and students I published Android Mobile Programming book written in Java which was recommended supplementary text book in Turkish universities in 2017. I have also contributed to and co-authored in a number of scientific research and publications.



### **Books**

### **Android Sanati - Android Mobile Programming Book**

(Gulbala Salamov<sup>1</sup>, Volkan Gurbuz <sup>2</sup>) LEVEL Publishing House, Turkey (2017) ISBN 6058352766

https://www.kitapyurdu.com/kitap/android-sanati/434078.html



### Publications

### **Android Sanati - Android Mobile Programming Book**

(Gulbala Salamov<sup>1</sup>, Volkan Gurbuz<sup>2</sup>) LEVEL Publishing House, Turkey (2017) ISBN 6058352766

https://www.kitapyurdu.com/kitap/android-sanati/434078.html

# A Novel Portable Nanotechnology Approach for Targeted Cancer Therapy

2nd International Symposium on Multidisciplinary Studies Innovative Technologies (2018)

Authors: Bunyatova, U., Kocum C., Haberal E., Salamov G. https://ieeexplore.ieee.org/document/8567302

### **New Strategy of Distance Education**

Universal Journal of Educational Research, Horizon Research Publishing, USA (2014) Authors: Bunyatova, F., Salamov, G.

http://www.hrpub.org/journals/article\_info.php?aid=1578

### Simulation Learning Based on Formal-Logical and Fuzzy Logics

6th International Computer and Instructional Technologies Symposium, Turkey (2012)

Authors: Bunyatova, F., Salamov, G.

https://www.pegem.net/Akademi/kongre\_detay.aspx?id=137107

## Logic of Integrity, Fuzzy Logic and Knowledge Modelling For **Machine Education**

5th International Conference on Application of ICT, Azerbaijan (2011) Authors: Bunyatova, F., Salamov, G.

https://ieeexplore.ieee.org/document/6110956



### Certifications

IELTS Score: 6.5

2018



### Professional Membership

### **European Cooperation in Science and Technology (COST)** (2018 - )

Citizen Science Work Group Member WG2: Developer synergies with education, WG4: Enhance role of CS for civil society